The placid banks of the Ipiranga heard the resounding cry of a heroic folk
And the sun of Liberty in shining beams shone in the homeland's sky at that instant.
If the pledge of this equality, we managed to conquer with strong arm,
In thy bosom, O Freedom, our chest defieth death itself!
O beloved, idolized homeland, hail, hail!
Brazil, an intense dream, a vivid ray of love and hope descends to earth
If in thy comely, smiling and limpid sky, the image of the Cross blazes.
Giant by thine own nature, thou art beautiful, thou art strong, an impavid colossus,
And thy future mirrors that greatness.
Adored Land
Amongst a thousand others art thou, Brazil,  O beloved homeland!
Of the sons of this ground thou art kind mother,
Beloved homeland, Brazil!
Eternally lying on a splendid cradle, to the sound of the sea and under deep sky light
Thou flarest, O Brazil, crocket of America, illuminated by the sun of New World!
Than the showiest land, thy smiling, pretty prairies have more flowers
Our groves have more life, our life in thy bosom more loves
O beloved, idolized homeland, hail, hail!
Brazil, of eternal love be a symbol, the starred labarum which thou displayst
And say the laurel-green of thy pennant: 'Peace in the future and glory in the past.'
But if thou raisest the strong cudgel of Justice, thou wilt see that a son of thine flees not from battle,
Nor do those who love thee fear their own death.
Beloved Land,
Amongst a thousand others, art thou, Brazil, O beloved homeland!
Of the sons of this ground thou art gentle mother,
Beloved homeland, Brazil!